Fernanda Lages

Glenageary, Dublin, Ireland fernanda1lages@gmail.com

+353 89 228 0639

www.linkedin.com/in/fernanda-lages

Stamp 2 in Ireland (permission to work 20h/w during school term | 40h/w during holidays)

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Solution-focused, bilingual professional (Portuguese and English) with a BA in Business Administration and 10 years' experience working with data analysis, KPIs, and providing data-driven decisions to the stakeholders of a multinational bank, Brazil's #1 newspaper, and a top-three sugarcane agribusiness in Brazil, looking for opportunities to expand experience in areas involving data analysis, information technology and agile methodologies.

Fundamental qualities: analytical, strong interpersonal communication, problem-solving skills, organised and highly efficient.

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

Vinmar International

The Netherlands (remote from Dublin) Contractor in Commercial Sector

January 2021 - Present

• Supporting Business Analysis's team building analytics reports in Microsoft Excel.

Atvos Agribusiness – Odebrecht Construction Group

São Paulo, Brazil

Reporting Data Analyst in Supply Chain Performance Indicators

January 2018 - November 2019

Internship* in Supply Chain Performance Indicators

June 2017 - December 2017

- Atvos is the 3rd largest sugarcane agrobusiness company in Brazil; it belongs to the Odebrecht Construction Group;
- Working together with Supply Chains managers and the director to define which KPIs were to be measured, and having insights related to the business;
- Drive discussions with business stakeholders to understand their problems and requirements;
- Regularly tracking levels of backlog, attendance, purchase requisitions, PO cycle time, reduction cost, maverick spend, among others;
- Data extraction from Oracle, ETL and data visualisation in Excel, Power BI and Power Point;
- Supporting IT team during the ERP migration project (from Oracle to SAP S/4 Hana), validating tests in OA:
- Providing ad-roc analysis related to Supply Chain.

Internship* in Supply Chain

May 2016 - May 2017

- Strategic sourcing process for contracting fertilizers by SAP Ariba, focusing on attending internal customer's needs;
- Preparing RFQ, equalization map and other related documents;
- Negotiation of spot-purchases with suppliers;
- Inputting purchase orders and contracts into the Oracle system.

Folha de S.Paulo Newspaper

São Paulo, Brazil

Internship* in Circulation

October 2014 - March 2016

- Highest newspaper circulation in Brazil;
- Tracking market share, social media indicators and circulation performance of Folha and other relevant players;
- Analysing product sales by channels and reporting same to managers and directors;
- Measuring performance of logistic distribution in order to minimize failures in product delivery and rate service providers;
- Supporting Collections department in operational processes such as SAP and Oracle's routines.

BNP Paribas Bank

São Paulo, Brazil

Internship* in Credit Management Solutions

April 2012 - April 2014

- French multinational bank;
- Measuring production of credit proposals for LatAm, reporting pipeline to the Head Office in Paris;
- Translating credit proposals' cover page (from English to Portuguese);
- Updating customer portfolio in the internal systems;
- Following KYC process to new dients and CRM support;
- General support to credit manager and analysts in other activities such as getting companies' data from Bloomberg terminal.

Apprenticeship* in Corporate & Institutional Banking

July 2010 - March 2012

- Working together with CIB's assistant organising business trips for the team, managing director's agenda and supporting the team's professional needs;
- Supporting Energy & Commodity Finance team monitoring commodities prices, updating controller sheets, checking the status of financial transactions and collecting customers' documentation for opening an account.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Postgraduate Degree Fundamentals of Computing

TU Dublin Computer Science, Ireland

January 2022 - May 2022

General English and Cambridge Exam, Professional Development

Emerald Cultural Institute, Palmerston Park, Dublin 6, Ireland

February 2020 - December 2021

Data Analytics

Digital House School, São Paulo, Brazil

August 2019 - November 2019

 Providing data-driven business decisions through knowledge of ETL; exploratory data analysis; storytelling; creating data visualisations using Excel and Power BI; Agile and Scrum methodologies, SQL, Data Studio, Google Analytics and Tableau.

Bachelor's Degree in Business Administration

PUC-SP (Pontifícia Universidade Católica de São Paulo), Brazil

August 2013 - December 2017

SKILLS

Microsoft Tools: Advanced Word, Advanced Excel, Strong in PowerBI, Advanced PowerPoint, Outlook and Teams;

OOP: Python;

ERP: SAP and Oracle:

Further Skills: Beginner SQL and Tableau, Google Analytics;

Languages: Portuguese (Native) and English (C1).

INTERESTS

Volunteering work that has a social impact; book club; cultural exchange.

* All those programmes required to be working 30h/w.